<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kettle on Kraken Brewing</title>
    <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/tags/kettle/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kettle on Kraken Brewing</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 22:03:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/tags/kettle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fruited Kettle Sour</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2023-12-05-fruited-kettle-sour/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 22:03:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2023-12-05-fruited-kettle-sour/</guid>
      <description>Summer time means fruity sour. My homebrew shop is currently out of Wildbrew Philly sour, a strain of yeast that produces lactic acid as well as alcohol. This yeast has been my go-to for sours for the last couple of years, as it&amp;rsquo;s a lot less effort than kettle sours and produces similar results. However, I&amp;rsquo;m strapped for time given I want this beer done by Christmas, and Philly Sour isn&amp;rsquo;t really an option, so I&amp;rsquo;m going back to my kettle-sour roots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pavlova Sour (Christmas Sour) (Vanilla Passionfruit Gose)</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2021-11-13-pavlova-sour-christmas-sour-vanilla-passionfruit-gose/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 23:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2021-11-13-pavlova-sour-christmas-sour-vanilla-passionfruit-gose/</guid>
      <description>This Passionfruit and Vanilla sour was the next sour ale I had lined up in my list of fruited sours. This time around I&amp;rsquo;m using Lallemand&amp;rsquo;s Philly Sour yeast - A lactic acid producing yeast. This will be my first sour without using traditional kettle souring techniques with Lactobacillus Plantarum, so I&amp;rsquo;m interested to see how it turns out. Some people have said that this strain produces less lactic acid and thus less sourness than kettle souring, but this generally comes down to yeast health and fermentation conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
