<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fruit Beer on Kraken Brewing</title>
    <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/tags/fruit-beer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fruit Beer on Kraken Brewing</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 22:03:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/tags/fruit-beer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fruited Kettle Sour</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2023-12-05-fruited-kettle-sour/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 22:03:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2023-12-05-fruited-kettle-sour/</guid>
      <description>Summer time means fruity sour. My homebrew shop is currently out of Wildbrew Philly sour, a strain of yeast that produces lactic acid as well as alcohol. This yeast has been my go-to for sours for the last couple of years, as it&amp;rsquo;s a lot less effort than kettle sours and produces similar results. However, I&amp;rsquo;m strapped for time given I want this beer done by Christmas, and Philly Sour isn&amp;rsquo;t really an option, so I&amp;rsquo;m going back to my kettle-sour roots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beers &amp; Goals of 2023</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2022-12-26-beers-goals-of-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 05:21:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2022-12-26-beers-goals-of-2023/</guid>
      <description>2﻿022 was a good year for brewing - I definitely got back into the swing of things and was able to brew a lot more beer than in 2021. While there was some dud beers (mostly due to oxidation..), the beers in general definitely improved in quality. I recognised that I branched out in styles as well, experimenting with different spices and yeasts. Of these, the Beglian White Ale (Witbier), Aussie Sparkling Ale and Mango Lassi sour were 3 notable beers that involved new ways of brewing with spices and different hop varietals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mango Lassi Sour (Fruited Sour Ale)</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2022-05-24-planned-mango-lassi-sour-with-maleny-yogurt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 10:24:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2022-05-24-planned-mango-lassi-sour-with-maleny-yogurt/</guid>
      <description>The inspiration for this beer comes from the traditional Indian Lassi drink, a sweet or spiced yogurt-based drink, commonly flavoured with fruit such as Mango. Like my other sours, this beer will have wheat and oat additions to add body and fullness. I&amp;rsquo;ll also be adding some lactose to counteract the sourness add to the body of the beer. For the fruit addition, I&amp;rsquo;ll be adding about 4kg of pureed mango as well as 1L of mango pulp (or mango nectar if I cant find the pulp).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
