<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pacific on Kraken Brewing</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/pacific/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pacific on Kraken Brewing</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 22:25:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/pacific/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Stone &amp; Wood Clone #3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2022-12-27-stone-wood-clone-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 22:25:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2022-12-27-stone-wood-clone-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I﻿n an effort to refine the Stone &amp;amp; Wood clone from &lt;a href=&#34;https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2021-02-25-stone-wood-clone-2/&#34;&gt;this &lt;/a&gt;post, I&amp;rsquo;ve updated the recipe based on the results and inspiration from other sources (see link in notes). For the new batch, I&amp;rsquo;m adding some flaked wheat to add some more haze, and i&amp;rsquo;m lowering the percentage of ale malt. I&amp;rsquo;m also switching to american ale malt, in order to get a lighter colour. Finally, I&amp;rsquo;m increasing the dry hop to 100g and maintaining IBUs at around 22. I&amp;rsquo;m also experimenting with ascorbic acid (vitamin C) and sodium metabisulfite (SMB) during the dry hop, in an effort to reduce oxidation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stone &amp; Wood Clone #2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2021-02-25-stone-wood-clone-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 05:05:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2021-02-25-stone-wood-clone-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The second beer I ever made was my first time going all grain. This recipe (&lt;a href=&#34;https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2019-05-16-snw-clone-biab/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) was a Stone &amp;amp; Wood clone, designed to loosely resemble the beer. While this was one of the most successful beers I&amp;rsquo;ve made, I decided to re-do it, this time with a much better, fine-tuned setup. The aim of this is to get an understanding on the impact of changing certain aspects to a brew and how they affect the end result. The grain bill is remaining mostly the same, with slightly more Wheat malt and Carapils. I&amp;rsquo;ve also increased the hop additions, adding slightly more bitterness and hopstand additions. Furthermore, I&amp;rsquo;ve tweaked the water chemistry in order to favour a light, hoppy ale, while removing chloramine with campden tablets. The beer will be kegged, whereas previously it was bottled, presenting more chance for oxidation. &lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The updated recipe can be found here:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
