<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Session on Kraken Brewing</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/session/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Session on Kraken Brewing</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 05:05:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/session/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hazy Crusher (DDH Session NEIPA)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2023-12-27-hazy-crusher-ddh-session-neipa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 05:05:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2023-12-27-hazy-crusher-ddh-session-neipa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think this is my 3rd time making this beer, and I&amp;rsquo;m making it again because I think it&amp;rsquo;s great hazy ale. In the past, I&amp;rsquo;ve had issues around oxidation for these hoppy and oaty beers, but now I&amp;rsquo;m at a comfortable place with controlling oxidation through use of preservatives and techniques like closed transfers. When I ordered this beer, I could only get a hold of golden oat malt, which I decided to use. Due to that, the beer ended up a bit darker than I had hoped, but the taste was actually pretty damn good.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aussie Sparkling Ale</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2022-05-22-aussie-sparkling-ale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 23:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2022-05-22-aussie-sparkling-ale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided to make a basic Australian Ale after having some bad luck with hazy, hoppy beers oxidising. Hoppy Days Brewing Supplies had this recipe for a Sparkling Ale, reminiscent of Coopers Sparkling Ale. This beer makes use of Australian malts (Voyager Pale Compass) and Australian hops (Pride of Ringwood) for a boil addition. Yeast used was SafAle k-97, a traditional german ale yeast.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;sparkling-ale&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sparkling Ale&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HOPPY DAYS BREWING SUPPLIES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hoppy Days Hazy Crusher (Session Neipa)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2022-01-07-hoppy-days-hazy-crusher-session-neipa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 03:07:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2022-01-07-hoppy-days-hazy-crusher-session-neipa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a recipe I took from Hoppy Days Brewing Supplies (Brisbane), which is a session NEIPA. This beer features low bitterness, heavily fruity/critrus hops and a full body with plenty of high-protein malts. This brew makes use of Verdant IPA yeast, which will aid in creating this hazy, hoppy fruit bomb. Although i&amp;rsquo;ve brewed this beer before, the first time was a dump due to heavy oxidation. This time around, I&amp;rsquo;m utilising the Fermzilla 27L to do a pressurised, closed transfer ferment, to avoid any oxidation. Hops will be loaded into the collection container and purged with CO2, to remove any possibility of oxygen getting in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hazy Session IPA</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2020-10-30-hazy-session-ipa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 02:03:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2020-10-30-hazy-session-ipa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This recipe is adapted from the HoppyDays Hazy Crusher IPA, a hazy session IPA with low bitterness, low ABV and a large dry hop addition. The yeast being used for this beer is the new Verdant IPA yeast. &lt;br&gt;&#xA;Target mash pH: 5.4 (need 5ml lactic acid)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Target water profile: Approximately 2-1 chloride to sulfate&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hazy Session IPA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Brew Method: All Grain&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Style Name: American IPA&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Boil Time: 60 min&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Batch Size: 23 liters (fermentor volume)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Boil Size: 27 liters&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Boil Gravity: 1.048&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Efficiency: 70% (brew house)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
