<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stout on Kraken Brewing</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/stout/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stout on Kraken Brewing</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 05:28:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/stout/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Vanilla Milk Chocolate Stout</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2023-04-22-vanilla-milk-chocolate-stout/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 05:28:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2023-04-22-vanilla-milk-chocolate-stout/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I﻿t&amp;rsquo;s been a few years since I&amp;rsquo;ve done a stout, and winters coming up, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d give it another crack. The last stout I made was a &lt;a href=&#34;https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2019-12-12-dwarven-stout/&#34;&gt;coffee chocolate stout&lt;/a&gt;, which used cold-brew coffee and cacao nibs soaked in congac. It was pretty good, but I wanted to do something different this time. I&amp;rsquo;ll be keeping a similar grain bill and hops (Fuggles), but I&amp;rsquo;ll be adding lactose to round out the bitterness, and I&amp;rsquo;ll also be adding cacao nibs and 2 vanilla beans. These should add the vanilla and chocolate notes i&amp;rsquo;m after.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beers &amp; Goals of 2023</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2022-12-26-beers-goals-of-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 05:21:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2022-12-26-beers-goals-of-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2﻿022 was a good year for brewing - I definitely got back into the swing of things and was able to brew a lot more beer than in 2021. While there was some dud beers (mostly due to oxidation..), the beers in general definitely improved in quality. I recognised that I branched out in styles as well, experimenting with different spices and yeasts. Of these, the Beglian White Ale (Witbier), Aussie Sparkling Ale and Mango Lassi sour were 3 notable beers that involved new ways of brewing with spices and different hop varietals. While I tend to stick to the same styles, I&amp;rsquo;m keen to branch out and try new things, mainly to keep things fresh and exciting. I&amp;rsquo;m also keen to try new methods, improve the efficiencies of my current process, and work on the limitations I&amp;rsquo;m currently facing.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I﻿n 2023, I have a few notable brewing improvements and styles I&amp;rsquo;m excited to try. In no given order, these are:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dwarven Stout</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2019-12-12-dwarven-stout/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2019-12-12-dwarven-stout/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Designing the Recipe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;This time around, i’m going to be partly designing my own recipe for a coffee stout. This stout is basically going to follow these guidelines:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;-ABV between 5% and 7%.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;-Grain bill of 80% base malt + remaining specialty grains.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;-Between 30 and 40 IBUs from bittering additions of hops, with some at the end of the boil.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;-An Ale yeast with an attenuation of approximately 75% (Us-04/05 or wyeast 1056 American Ale)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;-A mash between 67c and 69c&lt;br&gt;&#xA;-Water chemistry adjusted to add hardness (increased calcium and carbonate)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;-2.5 volumes of C02&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
