<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Kraken Brewing</title>
    <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Kraken Brewing</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 03:07:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hoppy Days Hazy Crusher (Session Neipa)</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2022-01-07-hoppy-days-hazy-crusher-session-neipa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 03:07:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2022-01-07-hoppy-days-hazy-crusher-session-neipa/</guid>
      <description>This is a recipe I took from Hoppy Days Brewing Supplies (Brisbane), which is a session NEIPA. This beer features low bitterness, heavily fruity/critrus hops and a full body with plenty of high-protein malts. This brew makes use of Verdant IPA yeast, which will aid in creating this hazy, hoppy fruit bomb. Although i&amp;rsquo;ve brewed this beer before, the first time was a dump due to heavy oxidation. This time around, I&amp;rsquo;m utilising the Fermzilla 27L to do a pressurised, closed transfer ferment, to avoid any oxidation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pavlova Sour (Christmas Sour) (Vanilla Passionfruit Gose)</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2021-11-13-pavlova-sour-christmas-sour-vanilla-passionfruit-gose/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 23:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2021-11-13-pavlova-sour-christmas-sour-vanilla-passionfruit-gose/</guid>
      <description>\ This Passionfruit and Vanilla sour was the next sour ale I had lined up in my list of fruited sours. This time around I&amp;rsquo;m using Lallemand&amp;rsquo;s Philly Sour yeast - A lactic acid producing yeast. This will be my first sour without using traditional kettle souring techniques with Lactobacillus Plantarum, so I&amp;rsquo;m interested to see how it turns out. Some people have said that this strain produces less lactic acid and thus less sourness than kettle souring, but this generally comes down to yeast health and fermentation conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ballistic Hawaiian Haze Clone (DDH Pale Ale)</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2021-04-12-ballistic-hawaiian-haze-clone-ddh-pale-ale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 03:18:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2021-04-12-ballistic-hawaiian-haze-clone-ddh-pale-ale/</guid>
      <description>For my next clone, I&amp;rsquo;m going to attempt to replicate Ballistic Brewing&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Hawaiian Haze&amp;rdquo; DDH Pale Ale. The tasting notes for this beer have been descriped as juicy, pineapple, hoppy and citric. It&amp;rsquo;s light in colour with a solid haze. The hops used were Citra, Rakau, Pacifica and Mosaic. The malts are pale malt, rolled/flaked oats and rolled/flaked wheat. It has medium bitterness with 30 IBUs and an ABV of 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mango Sour (Gose)</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2021-04-12-mango-sour-gose/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 02:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2021-04-12-mango-sour-gose/</guid>
      <description>Time for another sour! This time it&amp;rsquo;s going to be Mango, utilising 3kg of mango puree. The process will be the same kettle sour as my previous ones:
- Flaked Oats will be added to give the beer body, mouthfeel and slight sweetness.
- Fruit addition will be added during primary/secondary to get a fresher flavour and avoid cooked-flavours.
- A mesh bag will be used to catch the fruit particles and make kegging easier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stone &amp; Wood Clone #2</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2021-02-25-stone-wood-clone-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 05:05:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2021-02-25-stone-wood-clone-2/</guid>
      <description>The second beer I ever made was my first time going all grain. This recipe (https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2019-05-16-snw-clone-biab/) was a Stone &amp;amp; Wood clone, designed to loosely resemble the beer. While this was one of the most successful beers I&amp;rsquo;ve made, I decided to re-do it, this time with a much better, fine-tuned setup. The aim of this is to get an understanding on the impact of changing certain aspects to a brew and how they affect the end result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hazy Session IPA</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2020-10-30-hazy-session-ipa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 02:03:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2020-10-30-hazy-session-ipa/</guid>
      <description>This recipe is adapted from the HoppyDays Hazy Crusher IPA, a hazy session IPA with low bitterness, low ABV and a large dry hop addition. The yeast being used for this beer is the new Verdant IPA yeast. Target mash pH: 5.4 (need 5ml lactic acid)
Target water profile: Approximately 2-1 chloride to sulfate
Hazy Session IPA
Brew Method: All Grain
Style Name: American IPA
Boil Time: 60 min
Batch Size: 23 liters (fermentor volume)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Sour (Berliner Weisse)</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2020-08-21-raspberry-sour-berliner-weisse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 09:07:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2020-08-21-raspberry-sour-berliner-weisse/</guid>
      <description>This sour is pretty much a copy of the strawberry sour/berliner weisse I did last time. The only changes i&amp;rsquo;m making this time around are:
- Adding more fruit (4kg) in a pureed form (wholesale) which contains 15% sugar. This will up the ABV so the grain bill will be lower than normal.
- Fruit addition will be added during primary/secondary to get a fresher flavour and remove cooked-flavours.
- A mesh bag will be used to catch the Raspberry particles and make kegging easier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Closed Transfer Guide</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2020-08-20-closed-transfer-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 02:55:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2020-08-20-closed-transfer-guide/</guid>
      <description>For future reference, I&amp;rsquo;m going to briefly run through the process for a closed transfer, both pressurised and un-pressurised. The goal of this method is to reduce oxidation/oxygen contact on fermented beer. Oxidation can hugely impact the flavour and appearance of a beer, giving it off-flavours or causing hop flavour and aroma to dissipate. Therefore, it is important to reduce oxygen contact when transferring finished beer, especially heavily hopped beer. These methods will be suited for the SS Brewtech Brew Bucket or other stainless fermenters that are pressure rated to at least 1-2psi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Balter XPA Clone</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2020-07-20-balter-xpa-clone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2020-07-20-balter-xpa-clone/</guid>
      <description>This beer was designed to clone Balter&amp;rsquo;s XPA and be close as possible to the original. The head brewers released the hops they used, but not the grains or yeast. The clone grist consisted primarily of American Pale malt with some wheat and carapils for body/head retention and some cara malt for malty flavour. The water profile was higher in calcium and suflate to accentuate the hops, of which were primarily citrus/fruity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>German Lager</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2020-06-01-german-lager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2020-06-01-german-lager/</guid>
      <description>This recipe was taken from Hoppy day&amp;rsquo;s recipe list as a standard german pilsener/lager. Grain bill was mostly german pilsener with some gladiator malt for head retention and body, as well as some acidulated malt to lower the mash pH and get as many fermentable sugars as possible. This was aided with a low mash temp. Yeast is Saflager 34/70 being fermented around 10-12c for 2 weeks with a 6-8 week lager in the keg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lemon Myrtle XPA</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2020-01-13-lemon-myrtle-xpa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2020-01-13-lemon-myrtle-xpa/</guid>
      <description>Lemon Myrtle XPA
Brew Method: All Grain
Style Name: American Pale Ale
Boil Time: 60 min
Batch Size: 21 liters (fermentor volume)
Boil Size: 27 liters
Boil Gravity: 1.037
Efficiency: 70% (brew house)
STATS:
Original Gravity: 1.048
Final Gravity: 1.009
ABV (standard): 5.16%
IBU (tinseth): 36.6
SRM (morey): 5.1
Mash pH: 0
FERMENTABLES:
3.8 kg – Pale Malt (80.9%)
0.5 kg – Wheat Malt (10.6%)
0.2 kg – Biscuit Malt (4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strawberry Sour</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2020-01-09-strawberry-sour/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2020-01-09-strawberry-sour/</guid>
      <description>This was my first fruit kettle sour/berliner weisse. I decided to go with pureed strawberries at the end of the boil and sour using IBS capsules. The wort was pre acidified with lactic acid and acidulated malt to aid the souring. Some citra hops were used to add a bit more depth and flavour and citrus backing to the beer. Next time I&amp;rsquo;d probably add the fruit in primary at the end of fermentation to get a fresher flavour, as boiling the strawberry made it taste slightly different and somewhat artificial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Saison</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2020-01-06-raspberry-saison/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2020-01-06-raspberry-saison/</guid>
      <description>Grain Bill
-Base is pilsner, Vienna and Wheat malt to add body, head and character with a slight maltiness from the Vienna. Acidulated malt to lower mash pH. Hops
-Bittering hops to give approximately 30 IBUs and add spicy and fruity notes.
-Kent Goldings, Saaz, or Willamette to add mild floral/herbal notes without overpowering the fruit.
Water Chemistry
Calcium: 50
Magnesium: 5
Sodium: 20
Chloride: 30
Sulfate: 100
-Higher sulfates will give aid in drying out the beer and accentuating the hops/fruit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leftover IPA</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2019-12-29-leftover-ipa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2019-12-29-leftover-ipa/</guid>
      <description>Distilled water will be used in order to customise the water chemistry (30L plus 2L of tap water for the remaining sparge). Adding 6.5g of calcium sulfate (gypsum), 3g of calcium chloride, 4g of magnesium sulfate (epsom salt) and 1 gram of baking sodat to the strike water will give a mash + sparge water profile of:
Calcium 74 ppm
Magnesium 13 ppm
Sodium 11 ppm
Chloride 50 ppm
Sulfate 165 ppm</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dwarven Stout</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2019-12-12-dwarven-stout/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2019-12-12-dwarven-stout/</guid>
      <description>Designing the Recipe
This time around, i’m going to be partly designing my own recipe for a coffee stout. This stout is basically going to follow these guidelines:
-ABV between 5% and 7%.
-Grain bill of 80% base malt + remaining specialty grains.
-Between 30 and 40 IBUs from bittering additions of hops, with some at the end of the boil.
-An Ale yeast with an attenuation of approximately 75% (Us-04/05 or wyeast 1056 American Ale)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mango IPA</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2019-11-10-mango-ipa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2019-11-10-mango-ipa/</guid>
      <description>This time around, I decided to go with a Mango IPA since I love mango and wanted to try making a fruit beer. I now have my Brewzilla 3.1 35L setup and a better, larger fermentation fridge. Hopefully this will up the quality of my homebrew and make the process a lot easier. The Mango is added during fermentation with the hops and left for a week or two.
Mango IPA</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Setup</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2019-11-10-new-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2019-11-10-new-setup/</guid>
      <description>Last week, I purchased the Brewzilla 3.1 35L all-in-one brewing system along with a few bits and pieces. I also bought a huge fermentation fridge that should let me control temperature a lot better. My next brewday (Mango IPA) will be the first using this new system after only using BIAB in the past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Juicy NEIPA BIAB</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2019-09-10-neipa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2019-09-10-neipa/</guid>
      <description>For my second attempt at BIAB, after the Stone &amp;amp; Wood replica, I decided to go with a popular NEIPA recipe. The beer is meant to be cloudy orange, with big juicy fruity notes and a nice thickness to it.
This time around, I decided I needed to control the fermentation temperature a little better. I picked up an Inkbird ITC-308 Wifi digital temperature controller and hooked it up to an old bar fridge with a heating element in order to keep the temperature stable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First All Grain BIAB</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2019-05-16-snw-clone-biab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2019-05-16-snw-clone-biab/</guid>
      <description>While my mead is fermenting, I decided i’ll make my second ever batch of beer. This time I decided to scale things up to 23L and go with an all grain Pacific Ale BIAB (similar to Stone and Wood). For this I bought a 35L brew pot as well as a 30L plastic fermenter with airlock and thermometer. The specs of the Pacific Ale are as follows:
Date: 24/5/19
Boil Time: 60 min</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Mead</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2019-05-16-mead/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2019-05-16-mead/</guid>
      <description>After just having completed my first ever beer (IPA), I decided i’d chuck something into the fermenter so something is constantly being brewed and I can get a larger fermenter for other beer batches. I decided to go with mead because it takes a while to ferment, it gets pretty strong, it’s easy to brew and it can be pretty tasty once its fully mellowed out. Specifications:
Date: 8/5/2019
Vessel: Glass Carboy</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
