<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Coffee on Kraken Brewing</title>
    <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/tags/coffee/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Coffee on Kraken Brewing</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 05:28:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/tags/coffee/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Vanilla Milk Chocolate Stout</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2023-04-22-vanilla-milk-chocolate-stout/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 05:28:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2023-04-22-vanilla-milk-chocolate-stout/</guid>
      <description>I﻿t&amp;rsquo;s been a few years since I&amp;rsquo;ve done a stout, and winters coming up, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d give it another crack. The last stout I made was a coffee chocolate stout, which used cold-brew coffee and cacao nibs soaked in congac. It was pretty good, but I wanted to do something different this time. I&amp;rsquo;ll be keeping a similar grain bill and hops (Fuggles), but I&amp;rsquo;ll be adding lactose to round out the bitterness, and I&amp;rsquo;ll also be adding cacao nibs and 2 vanilla beans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beers &amp; Goals of 2023</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2022-12-26-beers-goals-of-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 05:21:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2022-12-26-beers-goals-of-2023/</guid>
      <description>2﻿022 was a good year for brewing - I definitely got back into the swing of things and was able to brew a lot more beer than in 2021. While there was some dud beers (mostly due to oxidation..), the beers in general definitely improved in quality. I recognised that I branched out in styles as well, experimenting with different spices and yeasts. Of these, the Beglian White Ale (Witbier), Aussie Sparkling Ale and Mango Lassi sour were 3 notable beers that involved new ways of brewing with spices and different hop varietals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dwarven Stout</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2019-12-12-dwarven-stout/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2019-12-12-dwarven-stout/</guid>
      <description>Designing the Recipe
This time around, i’m going to be partly designing my own recipe for a coffee stout. This stout is basically going to follow these guidelines:
-ABV between 5% and 7%.
-Grain bill of 80% base malt + remaining specialty grains.
-Between 30 and 40 IBUs from bittering additions of hops, with some at the end of the boil.
-An Ale yeast with an attenuation of approximately 75% (Us-04/05 or wyeast 1056 American Ale)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
