<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>All-Grain on Kraken Brewing</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/all-grain/</link>
    <description>Recent content in All-Grain on Kraken Brewing</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 03:33:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/all-grain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bugalugs Dark Ale (Hoppy Days Brewing Clone)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2025-06-29-split-the-g-dark-ale/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 03:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2025-06-29-split-the-g-dark-ale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For this brew I&amp;rsquo;m making the &lt;a href=&#34;https://hoppydaysbrewingsupplies.com.au/product/bugalugs-dark-ale/&#34;&gt;Bugalugs Dark Ale from Hoppy Days Brewing Supplies&lt;/a&gt;. This is a British Brown Ale with a strong backbone of toffee and chocolate with a solid bitterness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The grain bill for this beer is built on a base of Voyager Veloria Schooner malt, with Munich malt adding depth and complexity. The colour and roasted character comes from Shepherds Delight, Dark Voodoo, and Carafa Special III malts, giving that classic toffee and chocolate profile without being overly roasty.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cryo Pop Hazy Pale Ale (Bracket Brewing Clone)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2024-03-29-cryo-pop-hazy-pale-ale-bracket-brewing-clone-copy-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 03:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2024-03-29-cryo-pop-hazy-pale-ale-bracket-brewing-clone-copy-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For this brew I&amp;rsquo;m trying out cryo hops for the first time in this &lt;a href=&#34;https://untappd.com/b/bracket-brewing-insert-name/5250659&#34;&gt;Bracket Brewing &amp;ldquo;Insert Name&amp;rdquo; hazy pale ale&lt;/a&gt;. This recipe was adapted from a homebrewer who queried bracket brewing on their hazy pale ale recipe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The grain bill for this beer is mostly pale malt, with a huge 30% of rolled oats and about 5% honey malt to give colour and a slightly sweeter/malty finish.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The hops for this beer are Motueka, Idaho#7 and &lt;a href=&#34;https://cryopopblend.com/&#34;&gt;Cryo Pop&lt;/a&gt;, previously known as trial blend TRI2304CR. Recent research suggests that high levels of monoterpene alcohols and polyfunctional thiols in a wort stream can create the conditions necessary for the yeast metabolism of hop-derived compounds, otherwise known as “biotransformation.” This hop blend has been developed to make use of briotransformation and to work as both a single hop or in conjunction with other tropical hop varietals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cryo Pop Hazy Pale Ale (Bracket Brewing Clone)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2024-03-29-cryo-pop-hazy-pale-ale-bracket-brewing-clone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 03:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2024-03-29-cryo-pop-hazy-pale-ale-bracket-brewing-clone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For this brew I&amp;rsquo;m trying out cryo hops for the first time in this &lt;a href=&#34;https://untappd.com/b/bracket-brewing-insert-name/5250659&#34;&gt;Bracket Brewing &amp;ldquo;Insert Name&amp;rdquo; hazy pale ale&lt;/a&gt;. This recipe was adapted from a homebrewer who queried bracket brewing on their hazy pale ale recipe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The grain bill for this beer is mostly pale malt, with a huge 30% of rolled oats and about 5% honey malt to give colour and a slightly sweeter/malty finish.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The hops for this beer are Motueka, Idaho#7 and &lt;a href=&#34;https://cryopopblend.com/&#34;&gt;Cryo Pop&lt;/a&gt;, previously known as trial blend TRI2304CR. Recent research suggests that high levels of monoterpene alcohols and polyfunctional thiols in a wort stream can create the conditions necessary for the yeast metabolism of hop-derived compounds, otherwise known as “biotransformation.” This hop blend has been developed to make use of briotransformation and to work as both a single hop or in conjunction with other tropical hop varietals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hazy Crusher (DDH Session NEIPA)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2023-12-27-hazy-crusher-ddh-session-neipa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 05:05:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2023-12-27-hazy-crusher-ddh-session-neipa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think this is my 3rd time making this beer, and I&amp;rsquo;m making it again because I think it&amp;rsquo;s great hazy ale. In the past, I&amp;rsquo;ve had issues around oxidation for these hoppy and oaty beers, but now I&amp;rsquo;m at a comfortable place with controlling oxidation through use of preservatives and techniques like closed transfers. When I ordered this beer, I could only get a hold of golden oat malt, which I decided to use. Due to that, the beer ended up a bit darker than I had hoped, but the taste was actually pretty damn good.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fruited Kettle Sour</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2023-12-05-fruited-kettle-sour/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 22:03:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2023-12-05-fruited-kettle-sour/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Summer time means fruity sour. My homebrew shop is currently out of Wildbrew Philly sour, a strain of yeast that produces lactic acid as well as alcohol. This yeast has been my go-to for sours for the last couple of years, as it&amp;rsquo;s a lot less effort than kettle sours and produces similar results. However, I&amp;rsquo;m strapped for time given I want this beer done by Christmas, and Philly Sour isn&amp;rsquo;t really an option, so I&amp;rsquo;m going back to my kettle-sour roots.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DDH Oat Cream Tropical Hazy IPA</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2023-03-02-ddh-oat-cream-tropical-hazy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 22:58:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2023-03-02-ddh-oat-cream-tropical-hazy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A﻿fter my last pacific/wheat ale, and success using sodium metabisulfite and ascorbic acid, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to take another crack at a Hazy IPA. This beer will feature Nectaron, which I&amp;rsquo;m trying for the first time, as well as BRU-1 and El Dorado, which I&amp;rsquo;ve had good results with in the past. As with my other Hazies, I&amp;rsquo;m aiming for a 2:1 chloride to sulfate ratio, heavy whirlpool and dry hop additions, and I&amp;rsquo;m looking to reduce oxidation as much as possible. I&amp;rsquo;ll be closed transferring under pressure and using SMB and ascorbic acid at my terminal dry hop.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stone &amp; Wood Clone #3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2022-12-27-stone-wood-clone-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 22:25:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2022-12-27-stone-wood-clone-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I﻿n an effort to refine the Stone &amp;amp; Wood clone from &lt;a href=&#34;https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2021-02-25-stone-wood-clone-2/&#34;&gt;this &lt;/a&gt;post, I&amp;rsquo;ve updated the recipe based on the results and inspiration from other sources (see link in notes). For the new batch, I&amp;rsquo;m adding some flaked wheat to add some more haze, and i&amp;rsquo;m lowering the percentage of ale malt. I&amp;rsquo;m also switching to american ale malt, in order to get a lighter colour. Finally, I&amp;rsquo;m increasing the dry hop to 100g and maintaining IBUs at around 22. I&amp;rsquo;m also experimenting with ascorbic acid (vitamin C) and sodium metabisulfite (SMB) during the dry hop, in an effort to reduce oxidation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blackberry Sour (Gose)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2022-11-12-berry-sour-gose/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 13:33:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2022-11-12-berry-sour-gose/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Going ahead with another fruited sour using the Philly Sour yeast. This time I think I&amp;rsquo;ll do a mix of darker fruits (Blackberry, Cherry &amp;amp; Raspberry) and see how that goes. Like my last sour, I&amp;rsquo;ve added some lactose to counteract the sourness. I also added some dextrose to the boil to give the yeast some glucose for lactic acid production. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably add the fruit around day 5-6, purge with some c02 and leave for 3-4 days until fermentation finishes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Safe Bet NEIPA</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2022-11-12-safe-bet-neipa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 13:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2022-11-12-safe-bet-neipa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;D﻿ecided to have another crack at a hoppy hazy with this recipe from some dude on Facebook. For this brew, I&amp;rsquo;m trying out suspending the hops in a bag using magnets.. as a final effort to avoid oxidation. Closed transfers don&amp;rsquo;t seem to be working well enough, and I figured it may be due to opening the fermenter for dry hop additions, so we&amp;rsquo;ll see how this goes. I kinda screwed it up though because the hop bag is too big for the fermenter headspace.. so now the hops are slightly touching the wort. I&amp;rsquo;ll try limit the fermentation time of this batch to not drag out the hop exposure. I also forgot to use a Whirfloc tablet, but it might help contribute some slight haze. Ultimate goal of this batch is to just avoid oxidation. I&amp;rsquo;m also trying liquid yeast for the first time (Bluestone Yeast Co. New England ale strain). Hopefully it goes well, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t cheap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aussie Sparkling Ale</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2022-05-22-aussie-sparkling-ale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 23:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2022-05-22-aussie-sparkling-ale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided to make a basic Australian Ale after having some bad luck with hazy, hoppy beers oxidising. Hoppy Days Brewing Supplies had this recipe for a Sparkling Ale, reminiscent of Coopers Sparkling Ale. This beer makes use of Australian malts (Voyager Pale Compass) and Australian hops (Pride of Ringwood) for a boil addition. Yeast used was SafAle k-97, a traditional german ale yeast.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;sparkling-ale&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sparkling Ale&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HOPPY DAYS BREWING SUPPLIES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hoppy Days Hazy Crusher (Session Neipa)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2022-01-07-hoppy-days-hazy-crusher-session-neipa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 03:07:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2022-01-07-hoppy-days-hazy-crusher-session-neipa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a recipe I took from Hoppy Days Brewing Supplies (Brisbane), which is a session NEIPA. This beer features low bitterness, heavily fruity/critrus hops and a full body with plenty of high-protein malts. This brew makes use of Verdant IPA yeast, which will aid in creating this hazy, hoppy fruit bomb. Although i&amp;rsquo;ve brewed this beer before, the first time was a dump due to heavy oxidation. This time around, I&amp;rsquo;m utilising the Fermzilla 27L to do a pressurised, closed transfer ferment, to avoid any oxidation. Hops will be loaded into the collection container and purged with CO2, to remove any possibility of oxygen getting in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pavlova Sour (Christmas Sour) (Vanilla Passionfruit Gose)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2021-11-13-pavlova-sour-christmas-sour-vanilla-passionfruit-gose/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 23:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2021-11-13-pavlova-sour-christmas-sour-vanilla-passionfruit-gose/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Passionfruit and Vanilla sour was the next sour ale I had lined up in my list of fruited sours. This time around I&amp;rsquo;m using Lallemand&amp;rsquo;s Philly Sour yeast - A lactic acid producing yeast. This will be my first sour without using traditional kettle souring techniques with Lactobacillus Plantarum, so I&amp;rsquo;m interested to see how it turns out. Some people have said that this strain produces less lactic acid and thus less sourness than kettle souring, but this generally comes down to yeast health and fermentation conditions. I&amp;rsquo;m fermenting at 23c, as a higher temperature supposedly encourages greater lactic acid production. As for the additions, I&amp;rsquo;m adding 2kg of frozen Passionfruit Pulp from Hoppy Days Brewing Supplies in Brisbane. I&amp;rsquo;m also adding about 10ml of Vanilla Extract and 250g of Lactose to the boil (to counteract the sourness of the passionfruit and lactic acid). I&amp;rsquo;m aiming for a pH of around 3.3 and a FG of about 1.015, to give an ABV of approximately 5.4%.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Balter XPA Clone</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2020-07-20-balter-xpa-clone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2020-07-20-balter-xpa-clone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This beer was designed to clone Balter&amp;rsquo;s XPA and be close as possible to the original. The head brewers released the hops they used, but not the grains or yeast. The clone grist consisted primarily of American Pale malt with some wheat and carapils for body/head retention and some cara malt for malty flavour. The water profile was higher in calcium and suflate to accentuate the hops, of which were primarily citrus/fruity. Mash was mid 60&amp;rsquo;s to increase fermentable sugar content and produce a semi-dry beer using US-05.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
