<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sour on Kraken Brewing</title>
    <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/tags/sour/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sour on Kraken Brewing</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 02:28:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/tags/sour/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mango Sour (Gose)</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2021-04-12-mango-sour-gose/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 02:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2021-04-12-mango-sour-gose/</guid>
      <description>Time for another sour! This time it&amp;rsquo;s going to be Mango, utilising 3kg of mango puree. The process will be the same kettle sour as my previous ones:
- Flaked Oats will be added to give the beer body, mouthfeel and slight sweetness.
- Fruit addition will be added during primary/secondary to get a fresher flavour and avoid cooked-flavours.
- A mesh bag will be used to catch the fruit particles and make kegging easier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Sour (Berliner Weisse)</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2020-08-21-raspberry-sour-berliner-weisse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 09:07:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2020-08-21-raspberry-sour-berliner-weisse/</guid>
      <description>This sour is pretty much a copy of the strawberry sour/berliner weisse I did last time. The only changes i&amp;rsquo;m making this time around are:
- Adding more fruit (4kg) in a pureed form (wholesale) which contains 15% sugar. This will up the ABV so the grain bill will be lower than normal.
- Fruit addition will be added during primary/secondary to get a fresher flavour and remove cooked-flavours.
- A mesh bag will be used to catch the Raspberry particles and make kegging easier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strawberry Sour</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2020-01-09-strawberry-sour/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2020-01-09-strawberry-sour/</guid>
      <description>This was my first fruit kettle sour/berliner weisse. I decided to go with pureed strawberries at the end of the boil and sour using IBS capsules. The wort was pre acidified with lactic acid and acidulated malt to aid the souring. Some citra hops were used to add a bit more depth and flavour and citrus backing to the beer. Next time I&amp;rsquo;d probably add the fruit in primary at the end of fermentation to get a fresher flavour, as boiling the strawberry made it taste slightly different and somewhat artificial.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>