<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hazy on Kraken Brewing</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/hazy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hazy on Kraken Brewing</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 03:33:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/hazy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cryo Pop Hazy Pale Ale (Bracket Brewing Clone)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2024-03-29-cryo-pop-hazy-pale-ale-bracket-brewing-clone-copy-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 03:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2024-03-29-cryo-pop-hazy-pale-ale-bracket-brewing-clone-copy-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For this brew I&amp;rsquo;m trying out cryo hops for the first time in this &lt;a href=&#34;https://untappd.com/b/bracket-brewing-insert-name/5250659&#34;&gt;Bracket Brewing &amp;ldquo;Insert Name&amp;rdquo; hazy pale ale&lt;/a&gt;. This recipe was adapted from a homebrewer who queried bracket brewing on their hazy pale ale recipe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The grain bill for this beer is mostly pale malt, with a huge 30% of rolled oats and about 5% honey malt to give colour and a slightly sweeter/malty finish.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The hops for this beer are Motueka, Idaho#7 and &lt;a href=&#34;https://cryopopblend.com/&#34;&gt;Cryo Pop&lt;/a&gt;, previously known as trial blend TRI2304CR. Recent research suggests that high levels of monoterpene alcohols and polyfunctional thiols in a wort stream can create the conditions necessary for the yeast metabolism of hop-derived compounds, otherwise known as “biotransformation.” This hop blend has been developed to make use of briotransformation and to work as both a single hop or in conjunction with other tropical hop varietals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cryo Pop Hazy Pale Ale (Bracket Brewing Clone)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2024-03-29-cryo-pop-hazy-pale-ale-bracket-brewing-clone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 03:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2024-03-29-cryo-pop-hazy-pale-ale-bracket-brewing-clone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For this brew I&amp;rsquo;m trying out cryo hops for the first time in this &lt;a href=&#34;https://untappd.com/b/bracket-brewing-insert-name/5250659&#34;&gt;Bracket Brewing &amp;ldquo;Insert Name&amp;rdquo; hazy pale ale&lt;/a&gt;. This recipe was adapted from a homebrewer who queried bracket brewing on their hazy pale ale recipe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The grain bill for this beer is mostly pale malt, with a huge 30% of rolled oats and about 5% honey malt to give colour and a slightly sweeter/malty finish.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The hops for this beer are Motueka, Idaho#7 and &lt;a href=&#34;https://cryopopblend.com/&#34;&gt;Cryo Pop&lt;/a&gt;, previously known as trial blend TRI2304CR. Recent research suggests that high levels of monoterpene alcohols and polyfunctional thiols in a wort stream can create the conditions necessary for the yeast metabolism of hop-derived compounds, otherwise known as “biotransformation.” This hop blend has been developed to make use of briotransformation and to work as both a single hop or in conjunction with other tropical hop varietals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hazy Crusher (DDH Session NEIPA)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2023-12-27-hazy-crusher-ddh-session-neipa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 05:05:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2023-12-27-hazy-crusher-ddh-session-neipa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think this is my 3rd time making this beer, and I&amp;rsquo;m making it again because I think it&amp;rsquo;s great hazy ale. In the past, I&amp;rsquo;ve had issues around oxidation for these hoppy and oaty beers, but now I&amp;rsquo;m at a comfortable place with controlling oxidation through use of preservatives and techniques like closed transfers. When I ordered this beer, I could only get a hold of golden oat malt, which I decided to use. Due to that, the beer ended up a bit darker than I had hoped, but the taste was actually pretty damn good.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DDH Oat Cream Tropical Hazy IPA</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2023-03-02-ddh-oat-cream-tropical-hazy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 22:58:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2023-03-02-ddh-oat-cream-tropical-hazy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A﻿fter my last pacific/wheat ale, and success using sodium metabisulfite and ascorbic acid, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to take another crack at a Hazy IPA. This beer will feature Nectaron, which I&amp;rsquo;m trying for the first time, as well as BRU-1 and El Dorado, which I&amp;rsquo;ve had good results with in the past. As with my other Hazies, I&amp;rsquo;m aiming for a 2:1 chloride to sulfate ratio, heavy whirlpool and dry hop additions, and I&amp;rsquo;m looking to reduce oxidation as much as possible. I&amp;rsquo;ll be closed transferring under pressure and using SMB and ascorbic acid at my terminal dry hop.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stone &amp; Wood Clone #3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2022-12-27-stone-wood-clone-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 22:25:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2022-12-27-stone-wood-clone-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I﻿n an effort to refine the Stone &amp;amp; Wood clone from &lt;a href=&#34;https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2021-02-25-stone-wood-clone-2/&#34;&gt;this &lt;/a&gt;post, I&amp;rsquo;ve updated the recipe based on the results and inspiration from other sources (see link in notes). For the new batch, I&amp;rsquo;m adding some flaked wheat to add some more haze, and i&amp;rsquo;m lowering the percentage of ale malt. I&amp;rsquo;m also switching to american ale malt, in order to get a lighter colour. Finally, I&amp;rsquo;m increasing the dry hop to 100g and maintaining IBUs at around 22. I&amp;rsquo;m also experimenting with ascorbic acid (vitamin C) and sodium metabisulfite (SMB) during the dry hop, in an effort to reduce oxidation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Safe Bet NEIPA</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2022-11-12-safe-bet-neipa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 13:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2022-11-12-safe-bet-neipa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;D﻿ecided to have another crack at a hoppy hazy with this recipe from some dude on Facebook. For this brew, I&amp;rsquo;m trying out suspending the hops in a bag using magnets.. as a final effort to avoid oxidation. Closed transfers don&amp;rsquo;t seem to be working well enough, and I figured it may be due to opening the fermenter for dry hop additions, so we&amp;rsquo;ll see how this goes. I kinda screwed it up though because the hop bag is too big for the fermenter headspace.. so now the hops are slightly touching the wort. I&amp;rsquo;ll try limit the fermentation time of this batch to not drag out the hop exposure. I also forgot to use a Whirfloc tablet, but it might help contribute some slight haze. Ultimate goal of this batch is to just avoid oxidation. I&amp;rsquo;m also trying liquid yeast for the first time (Bluestone Yeast Co. New England ale strain). Hopefully it goes well, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t cheap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hoppy Days Hazy Crusher (Session Neipa)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2022-01-07-hoppy-days-hazy-crusher-session-neipa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 03:07:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2022-01-07-hoppy-days-hazy-crusher-session-neipa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a recipe I took from Hoppy Days Brewing Supplies (Brisbane), which is a session NEIPA. This beer features low bitterness, heavily fruity/critrus hops and a full body with plenty of high-protein malts. This brew makes use of Verdant IPA yeast, which will aid in creating this hazy, hoppy fruit bomb. Although i&amp;rsquo;ve brewed this beer before, the first time was a dump due to heavy oxidation. This time around, I&amp;rsquo;m utilising the Fermzilla 27L to do a pressurised, closed transfer ferment, to avoid any oxidation. Hops will be loaded into the collection container and purged with CO2, to remove any possibility of oxygen getting in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ballistic Hawaiian Haze Clone (DDH Pale Ale)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2021-04-12-ballistic-hawaiian-haze-clone-ddh-pale-ale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 03:18:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2021-04-12-ballistic-hawaiian-haze-clone-ddh-pale-ale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For my next clone, I&amp;rsquo;m going to attempt to replicate Ballistic Brewing&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Hawaiian Haze&amp;rdquo; DDH Pale Ale. The tasting notes for this beer have been descriped as juicy, pineapple, hoppy and citric. It&amp;rsquo;s light in colour with a solid haze. The hops used were Citra, Rakau, Pacifica and Mosaic. The malts are pale malt, rolled/flaked oats and rolled/flaked wheat. It has medium bitterness with 30 IBUs and an ABV of 4.6%. Using this information, I plan to make a recipe that replicates the beer as closely as possible.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Grain Bill&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;-Use of high protein grains such as flaked oats and wheat. &lt;br&gt;&#xA;-Marris Otter base, with some wheat malt, flaked oats and flaked wheat &lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Hops&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;-Citra, Rakau, Pacifica and Mosaic, targetting 30 IBU in the boil with late additions and a substantial dry hop. The whirlpool should make up majority of the hop boil additions, aiming for 80-85c additions. &lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Chemistry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;-a 2:1 Chloride to Sulfate ratio will accentuate the smooth malt body and not the hops, as they speak for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hazy Session IPA</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2020-10-30-hazy-session-ipa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 02:03:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2020-10-30-hazy-session-ipa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This recipe is adapted from the HoppyDays Hazy Crusher IPA, a hazy session IPA with low bitterness, low ABV and a large dry hop addition. The yeast being used for this beer is the new Verdant IPA yeast. &lt;br&gt;&#xA;Target mash pH: 5.4 (need 5ml lactic acid)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Target water profile: Approximately 2-1 chloride to sulfate&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hazy Session IPA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Brew Method: All Grain&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Style Name: American IPA&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Boil Time: 60 min&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Batch Size: 23 liters (fermentor volume)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Boil Size: 27 liters&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Boil Gravity: 1.048&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Efficiency: 70% (brew house)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
