<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fruit on Kraken Brewing</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/fruit/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fruit on Kraken Brewing</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 22:03:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/fruit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fruited Kettle Sour</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2023-12-05-fruited-kettle-sour/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 22:03:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2023-12-05-fruited-kettle-sour/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Summer time means fruity sour. My homebrew shop is currently out of Wildbrew Philly sour, a strain of yeast that produces lactic acid as well as alcohol. This yeast has been my go-to for sours for the last couple of years, as it&amp;rsquo;s a lot less effort than kettle sours and produces similar results. However, I&amp;rsquo;m strapped for time given I want this beer done by Christmas, and Philly Sour isn&amp;rsquo;t really an option, so I&amp;rsquo;m going back to my kettle-sour roots.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pavlova Sour (Christmas Sour) (Vanilla Passionfruit Gose)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2021-11-13-pavlova-sour-christmas-sour-vanilla-passionfruit-gose/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 23:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2021-11-13-pavlova-sour-christmas-sour-vanilla-passionfruit-gose/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Passionfruit and Vanilla sour was the next sour ale I had lined up in my list of fruited sours. This time around I&amp;rsquo;m using Lallemand&amp;rsquo;s Philly Sour yeast - A lactic acid producing yeast. This will be my first sour without using traditional kettle souring techniques with Lactobacillus Plantarum, so I&amp;rsquo;m interested to see how it turns out. Some people have said that this strain produces less lactic acid and thus less sourness than kettle souring, but this generally comes down to yeast health and fermentation conditions. I&amp;rsquo;m fermenting at 23c, as a higher temperature supposedly encourages greater lactic acid production. As for the additions, I&amp;rsquo;m adding 2kg of frozen Passionfruit Pulp from Hoppy Days Brewing Supplies in Brisbane. I&amp;rsquo;m also adding about 10ml of Vanilla Extract and 250g of Lactose to the boil (to counteract the sourness of the passionfruit and lactic acid). I&amp;rsquo;m aiming for a pH of around 3.3 and a FG of about 1.015, to give an ABV of approximately 5.4%.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mango Sour (Gose)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2021-04-12-mango-sour-gose/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 02:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2021-04-12-mango-sour-gose/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Time for another sour! This time it&amp;rsquo;s going to be Mango, utilising 3kg of mango puree. The process will be the same kettle sour as my previous ones:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;- Flaked Oats will be added to give the beer body, mouthfeel and slight sweetness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;- Fruit addition will be added during primary/secondary to get a fresher flavour and avoid cooked-flavours.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;- A mesh bag will be used to catch the fruit particles and make kegging easier.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Sour (Berliner Weisse)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2020-08-21-raspberry-sour-berliner-weisse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 09:07:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2020-08-21-raspberry-sour-berliner-weisse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This sour is pretty much a copy of the strawberry sour/berliner weisse I did last time. The only changes i&amp;rsquo;m making this time around are:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;- Adding more fruit (4kg) in a pureed form (wholesale) which contains 15% sugar. This will up the ABV so the grain bill will be lower than normal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;- Fruit addition will be added during primary/secondary to get a fresher flavour and remove cooked-flavours.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;- A mesh bag will be used to catch the Raspberry particles and make kegging easier.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
