<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ale on Kraken Brewing</title>
    <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/tags/ale/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ale on Kraken Brewing</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 13:33:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/tags/ale/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Blackberry Sour (Gose)</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2022-11-12-berry-sour-gose/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 13:33:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2022-11-12-berry-sour-gose/</guid>
      <description>Going ahead with another fruited sour using the Philly Sour yeast. This time I think I&amp;rsquo;ll do a mix of darker fruits (Blackberry, Cherry &amp;amp; Raspberry) and see how that goes. Like my last sour, I&amp;rsquo;ve added some lactose to counteract the sourness. I also added some dextrose to the boil to give the yeast some glucose for lactic acid production. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably add the fruit around day 5-6, purge with some c02 and leave for 3-4 days until fermentation finishes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safe Bet NEIPA</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2022-11-12-safe-bet-neipa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 13:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2022-11-12-safe-bet-neipa/</guid>
      <description>D﻿ecided to have another crack at a hoppy hazy with this recipe from some dude on Facebook. For this brew, I&amp;rsquo;m trying out suspending the hops in a bag using magnets.. as a final effort to avoid oxidation. Closed transfers don&amp;rsquo;t seem to be working well enough, and I figured it may be due to opening the fermenter for dry hop additions, so we&amp;rsquo;ll see how this goes. I kinda screwed it up though because the hop bag is too big for the fermenter headspace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Belgian Witbier (White ale)</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2022-08-31-belgian-witbier-white-ale/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 23:46:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2022-08-31-belgian-witbier-white-ale/</guid>
      <description>The inspiration for this beer came from a night several years ago when I was working as a bartender. Myself and a few others headed to an American-style bar across the road on our break, for some food and beers. I ended up getting a Blue Moon on tap, not knowing what it is and expecting it to be a thin, watered down American lager. I was surprised to receive the opposite, a full-bodied, rich, citrusy and spicy Belgian-style ale with a slice of orange in it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mango Lassi Sour (Fruited Sour Ale)</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2022-05-24-planned-mango-lassi-sour-with-maleny-yogurt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 10:24:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2022-05-24-planned-mango-lassi-sour-with-maleny-yogurt/</guid>
      <description>The inspiration for this beer comes from the traditional Indian Lassi drink, a sweet or spiced yogurt-based drink, commonly flavoured with fruit such as Mango. Like my other sours, this beer will have wheat and oat additions to add body and fullness. I&amp;rsquo;ll also be adding some lactose to counteract the sourness add to the body of the beer. For the fruit addition, I&amp;rsquo;ll be adding about 4kg of pureed mango as well as 1L of mango pulp (or mango nectar if I cant find the pulp).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ballistic Hawaiian Haze Clone (DDH Pale Ale)</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2021-04-12-ballistic-hawaiian-haze-clone-ddh-pale-ale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 03:18:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2021-04-12-ballistic-hawaiian-haze-clone-ddh-pale-ale/</guid>
      <description>For my next clone, I&amp;rsquo;m going to attempt to replicate Ballistic Brewing&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Hawaiian Haze&amp;rdquo; DDH Pale Ale. The tasting notes for this beer have been descriped as juicy, pineapple, hoppy and citric. It&amp;rsquo;s light in colour with a solid haze. The hops used were Citra, Rakau, Pacifica and Mosaic. The malts are pale malt, rolled/flaked oats and rolled/flaked wheat. It has medium bitterness with 30 IBUs and an ABV of 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mango Sour (Gose)</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2021-04-12-mango-sour-gose/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 02:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2021-04-12-mango-sour-gose/</guid>
      <description>Time for another sour! This time it&amp;rsquo;s going to be Mango, utilising 3kg of mango puree. The process will be the same kettle sour as my previous ones:
- Flaked Oats will be added to give the beer body, mouthfeel and slight sweetness.
- Fruit addition will be added during primary/secondary to get a fresher flavour and avoid cooked-flavours.
- A mesh bag will be used to catch the fruit particles and make kegging easier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stone &amp; Wood Clone #2</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2021-02-25-stone-wood-clone-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 05:05:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2021-02-25-stone-wood-clone-2/</guid>
      <description>The second beer I ever made was my first time going all grain. This recipe (https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2019-05-16-snw-clone-biab/) was a Stone &amp;amp; Wood clone, designed to loosely resemble the beer. While this was one of the most successful beers I&amp;rsquo;ve made, I decided to re-do it, this time with a much better, fine-tuned setup. The aim of this is to get an understanding on the impact of changing certain aspects to a brew and how they affect the end result.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
