<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Clone on Kraken Brewing</title>
    <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/tags/clone/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Clone on Kraken Brewing</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 03:18:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/tags/clone/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ballistic Hawaiian Haze Clone (DDH Pale Ale)</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2021-04-12-ballistic-hawaiian-haze-clone-ddh-pale-ale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 03:18:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2021-04-12-ballistic-hawaiian-haze-clone-ddh-pale-ale/</guid>
      <description>For my next clone, I&amp;rsquo;m going to attempt to replicate Ballistic Brewing&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Hawaiian Haze&amp;rdquo; DDH Pale Ale. The tasting notes for this beer have been descriped as juicy, pineapple, hoppy and citric. It&amp;rsquo;s light in colour with a solid haze. The hops used were Citra, Rakau, Pacifica and Mosaic. The malts are pale malt, rolled/flaked oats and rolled/flaked wheat. It has medium bitterness with 30 IBUs and an ABV of 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stone &amp; Wood Clone #2</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2021-02-25-stone-wood-clone-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 05:05:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2021-02-25-stone-wood-clone-2/</guid>
      <description>The second beer I ever made was my first time going all grain. This recipe (https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2019-05-16-snw-clone-biab/) was a Stone &amp;amp; Wood clone, designed to loosely resemble the beer. While this was one of the most successful beers I&amp;rsquo;ve made, I decided to re-do it, this time with a much better, fine-tuned setup. The aim of this is to get an understanding on the impact of changing certain aspects to a brew and how they affect the end result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Balter XPA Clone</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2020-07-20-balter-xpa-clone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2020-07-20-balter-xpa-clone/</guid>
      <description>This beer was designed to clone Balter&amp;rsquo;s XPA and be close as possible to the original. The head brewers released the hops they used, but not the grains or yeast. The clone grist consisted primarily of American Pale malt with some wheat and carapils for body/head retention and some cara malt for malty flavour. The water profile was higher in calcium and suflate to accentuate the hops, of which were primarily citrus/fruity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First All Grain BIAB</title>
      <link>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2019-05-16-snw-clone-biab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>luketryan95@gmail.com (Luke Ryan)</author>
      <guid>https://krakenbrewing.netlify.app/post/2019-05-16-snw-clone-biab/</guid>
      <description>While my mead is fermenting, I decided i’ll make my second ever batch of beer. This time I decided to scale things up to 23L and go with an all grain Pacific Ale BIAB (similar to Stone and Wood). For this I bought a 35L brew pot as well as a 30L plastic fermenter with airlock and thermometer. The specs of the Pacific Ale are as follows:
Date: 24/5/19
Boil Time: 60 min</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>